## SUBHAM SWAIN

## FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

### **Objective**

A Software developer with 2.0 years of experience in maintaining and building web pages and helping companies create and maintain a better code base for reusability. Capable of continuous learning from senior developers.. Having experience in HTML, CSS, javascript, React js, Redux, Nodejs, AWS, mongo db, Python, Djang

#### **Contact**

Mobile no-7008819985

Email-

subhamswain00@gmail.com

Linkedin-

https://tinyurl.com/linkdedn

Github-

https://tinyurl. com/Gitsubh

#### **Education**

Graduation in Biju Pattnaik Of University (BPUT), Odisha

B.TechinComputerScience and Engineering

Aug 2015-Oct 2019

7.7 CGPA

### **Technical Skills**

- · React.js
- · Python
- · Django,Rest Api
- · Express js
- · MongoDB, Postgresql, Mysql
- · Node Js
- · Html, CSS, Javascript
- · Redux
- · AWS,EC2,S3
- FastApi
- Flask

#### **Competencies**

- · Teamwork
- · Self-motivation
- Adaptability
- · Decision Making

#### Languages

- · Hindi
- English
- · Odia

#### **Experience**

Anand rathi wealth pvt ltd Software Engineer (Jan 2024-Present) | Mumbai Have created Python Applications and developed for Indian oil corporation limited to update their retails data and third party integration using Flask and Sql Alchemy and libraries to enhance application functionality.

#### Target Integration | Trainee Software Developer(Dec 2022-Jan 2023) | Bang

Developed new features and improved existing functionality in web applications collaborated with other developers and designed to deliver a high-quality product. Participated in code review to ensure code quality.

#### IWCN|Application Developer(Aug 2021-Nov 2022) | Agra

Designed and created low latency API between frontend and backend and made dashboard And authentication of users using Python and React JS and implementing new features from scratch. Worked with large and small team sizes.

#### **Projects**

Project - WorkStation(Postgresql,Python,Flask,SQL Alchemy,React Js,Redux,AWSEC2,S3,API GATEWAY,Lambda) (AnandRathi wealth Pvt) WorkStation is a product where it shows the information of client about equity,brokerage,mutual fund details .Improved API performance by fine-tuning Postregsql queries and SqlAlchemy ORM using Flask Integrated third-party AccordApi. Worked on the integration of backend and frontend and deployment using AWS and used AWS S3,EC2,Lambda.Utilized Axios to access API information for complex features on UI, in frontend using React Js

# Flamingo Rat | Node js, Express js, Mongo DB, React js, Websocket, HTML, CSS, Javascript (Target Integration)

It is an encryption and decryption system, so 2 windows one is for the client and another is for the server. So when the client messages something to the server will receive the message in encryption form. So server will decryption that message and read to understand what the client asked same thing the server will send the message in encryption and the client receives it and decryption that message.

# $Cynthex \parallel HTML \mid CSS \parallel Javascript \parallel Python \parallel Django \parallel React \parallel Redux(IWCN)$

Cynthex is used for the management of user-side application. Cynthex works as a custom Django admin. It is easy to use and the admin will able to manage all activities of users without having prior technical knowledge. Admin will able to chat with the user and will able to log out all user, disable and delete all users.